PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

ECM consultant with 10+ years of experience in Enterprise Application Management, this includes requirement analysis, design, coding, testing, system test support, implementation through various environments and post implementation support of various IBM FileNet based Java/J2ee applications. Have worked extensively in IBM FileNet platform and have been involved in the design, development, administration, upgrade and deployment of FileNet and CMOD products.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Penta Consulting, South Africa

Nov 2017 - present

IBM FileNet Consultant at Nedbank Ltd, Johannesburg

The Client is one of the largest banks in South Africa and they have implemented a full stack of IBM products for their ECM solution.

Responsibilities:

Point of Contact for ECM solutions

All L3 issues for ECM solutions (FileNet and CMOD); technical design, costing etc. for new ECM initiatives and generic queries/training around ECM products.

Rest of Africa archiving

The project is to migrate all client statements from legacy system to IBM FileNet and CMOD. It is to be implemented across six countries in Africa. My role is to plan the end to end implementation, from ECM perspective, and engage with other teams to develop and implement the solution.

CMOD Upgrade

Planning for the upgrade of CMOD stack from version 9.5 to version 10.1. Working on the detailed design and coordinating with other teams.

Path Infotech, Singapore

June 2016 – Oct 2017

Senior Consultant at Deutsche Bank Singapore.

The Client is a leader in Private Wealth management in APAC region. Their ECM setup contains IBM CMOD, IBM FileNet, Kofax capture and IBM Case Manager. The client required a senior consultant to own the ECM solution and help in activities like change management, coordination with other applications, L3 level support. Also looking for an experienced resource to coordinate the migration of ECM solution from CMOD to FileNet.

Responsibilities:

Integration/Coordination with other applications

The application is integrated with core banking system, mobile notification application, client onboarding application and others. I am coordinating and facilitating these applications to integrate with the IBM CMOD setup to archive and retrieve documents. Recently coordinated with Kofax and Lexmark consultants to modify a scanning solution for the application.

ECM application ownership

GAURAV PAINULY



Linkedin Profile

Date of Birth: 27-Mar-1982
Phone (home) +918171937963
E-mail: gauravpainuly@gmail.com

Technologies :IBM FileNet P8 3.5.2, P8 4.0 and P8 5.1, IBM Case Manager 5.2.0, IBM CMOD 8.5 and 9.5, Kofax .

<u>Languages</u> :Java, shell scripting,

XML, JavaScript, CSS

Environment :Windows

NT/2000/2003/XP/2008, AIX 5.3-6.1,

Linux

Databases :DB2 9.7, Oracle 9i-11i,

SQL Server

Tools :Eclipse 3.x, CVS, SQLDeveloper, putty, winscp

App Servers : JBoss 4.3, WebSphere 6.x, Tomcat 5.5.

Education:

Bachelor of Technology (Information Technology)

Uttar Pradesh Technological University

Have the technical ownership of the full ECM solution. Represent the solution in all technical and business discussions. Plan and prepare the changes being implemented in the ECM solution. Coordinate with different teams to develop, test and execute the change; prepare documentation and followup on the change management cycle. Plan and coordinate with the UAT and production support teams to support the ECM solution in the bank.

 $Plan\ and\ coordinate\ with\ the\ new\ applications\ wanting\ to\ use\ the\ ECM\ solution\ for\ document\ archival.$

ECM application migration

The client is to migrate the ECM solution from CMOD to FileNet case manager 5.2. I am coordinating with different architectural teams across different geographical location to design and document the solution. Also coordinating with vendor team to prepare the architectural design and migration approach. Procured servers for DEV and UAT environments for the upgrade and coordinating with IBM to install FileNet Case Manager 5.2.0 on the machines.

Hexaware Technologies, Mumbai

May 2014-June 2016

FileNet Upgrade / Development/Support Consultant

The Client is a well-established Financial Asset Management company based in NY. The client was working on IBM FileNet P8 4.5.1 product suite and the requirement was to upgrade to IBM FileNet P8 version 5.1. Along with upgrade the client also required support for existing P8 environment along with other ECM product being used in the client environment like IBM CMOD 8.5 and Adobe LiveCycle E4.

Responsibilities:

FileNet Upgrade

Involved in planning, preparing and implementing IBM FileNet P8 upgrade from version 4.5.1 to 5.1. Analyzed and resolved various issues encountered during upgrade. Helped DBA to resolve DB related upgrade issues. Raised changes related to upgrade and worked with team to complete them as per client process. Provided post-upgrade support to application owners and end-users.

FileNet Development

Created a Java utility to export documents stored in FileNet. The utility exported the document metadata in an XML and the attachment as PDFs. The exported data was further used as input to IBM CMOD. Co-ordinated with CMOD team to get the XML format correct and fix other import-export issues.

Reviewed and fixed bugs in a custom FileNet Java application deployed at client environment. Updated custom code in Workplace.

Created a Java utility to monitor IBM ICC services. If the services are down the utility sends email notification to support team.

Developed Java utility to generate reports from Content Engine, Process Engine and DB. The utility generates separate reports for items in Database, documents in CE and workitems in PE based on predefined filters.

FileNet Support

Provide L3 level support to application owners and end-users for FileNet based applications. Created a detailed Health-Check template for the client. The daily and weekly health check process implemented at client environment have helped proactively capture issues and fix them before users are online. Provide L1 support for CMOD 8.5 and Adobe LiveCycle E4. Provide support for DR activities. Provide weekend support for changes involving FileNet applications and other critical issues.

Wipro Ltd. / Defense Project

August 2013 – May 2014

Tech Lead (FileNet)

The Client is a one of the largest defense department in the world. EMMS is the Electronic Material Management System which is to be used by the client to digitize its asset maintenance process. IBM Maximo is used for Asset management while IBM FileNet is used as a Document Management system. Major technical challenges included SSO(Single Sign On) and integration with Maximo.

Responsibilities:

Tech Lead (FileNet)

Designed and developed SRS and Design documents.

Designed and developed solution for integration with Maximo.

Designed and developed solution for SSO in FileNet.

Designing solution for Technical publication with XMLs in FileNet.

IBM India Pvt. Ltd/ A major Telecomm company

Oct 2012 - Aug 2013

Team Leader

The client is a major Telecommunication company in India. ERM Enhancements was implemented for providing enhancements to the existing ERM application. ERM application is a case management tool built on FileNet architecture and Business Process Framework. This application is used to manage and resolve employee HR queries. HR Helpdesk agents resolve the queries or forward it to respective SME for the resolution through the tool. The tool also provides multiple reports to monitor raised queries and productivity of the agents.

Responsibilities:

Leading the project and mentor the team.

Designed and developed solution for BPF & USSD integration.

Designed and developed solution for case creation through SMS.

Designed and developed customized solution for performing action on multiple cases in bulk.

BPF Customization and workflow designing as per the user requirements.

IBM India Pvt. Ltd/ A major Telecomm company

Oct 2012 - Aug 2013

Team Leader

I was part of the team designing and implementing FileNet upgrade process. The upgrade is from P8 4.0 to P8 5.1. I prepared the HLD and LLD documents along with planning risks associated with the project.

Responsibilities:

Leading the project and mentor the team.

Prepared documentation regarding planning of the project after interacting with all technical teams involved in the project.

Found solutions to various issues related to migration that came up during POC.

Working with all the stakeholders to get the necessary approvals for go-live of the project.

Scope International, SCB, Chennai, India

Aug2010 - Oct2012

Senior Software Developer

SCB is one the largest banks serving Asian and African countries.

Responsibilities:

Upgrade

The organization underwent an upgrade of FileNet from P8 4.0 to P8 5.1. I was part of the design and documentation team. I was also part of raising many PMRs with IBM to sort out issues during testing.

Support

Supporting 11 FileNet based applications spread across 53 countries used by 17000+ employees. These applications use different FileNet component like CE, PE, AE, workplace, workplace XT, component manager, BPF, Rendition Engine, Records Crawler, Process Analyzer, CBR(Verity K2), Capture, Email Manager etc. Have knowledge of these components.

As part of PSS team worked on many change requests. It includes gathering requirements, cost estimation, approval, design, development, testing and deployment. Use the BMC Remedy tool to raise and follow up the change.

As part of BAU, in case of any issue, will analyse application and server logs. In case of issue with FileNet code will follow up with IBM via PMR.

Development

Worked on a utility that receives files through MQ series (ISIS) and uploads them in FileNet. Migrated 2 GB data in production using the utility.

Developed a utility to copy and transfer security on all object store elements while object store migration. Also made code to transfer marking sets too. The same code base is being used across organization as part of any production migration.

Developed utilities to launch process and terminate workitems.

Contentsilo Pvt Ltd, Dehradun, India

April2007 – July2010

Senior Software Developer

Responsibilities:

Designed and developed a contracts creator module to create documents into FileNet. Worked on the assembler module to allow users to assemble the contracts from the Broodcomb engine.

Created various contract related FileNet API calls to the Contracts Object store. Enterprise Contracts allows a user to build, process and manage contracts.

Implemented Path Navigation and Error Handling module in Enterprise Contracts.

The client had FileNet 3.5 and wanted a parent-child relationship between the document containing customer information and all the applications (saved as documents in the system) filed by him/her. Used XML to save and retrieve the relationship between the documents which was to be an attachment to the customer document. Updated the application workflow by adding a java component which will update the xml in the customer document whenever a new application was filed..

Created a project where a given XML, with a defined structure (Schema), had to be parsed and converted first into the standard XSL-FO format and then into various formats like PDF, MS WORD, MS EXCEL and text.. Created a configurable Google Web Toolkit based contracts editor that is being used with Enterprise Contracts. The editor reads the contracts xml file and parses it based on html tags. It also allows the user to export the contract in a contracts xml based format..